<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SLAM | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/slam/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/slam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SLAM</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>SLAM</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/slam/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAST_LIO_SAM for Multi-sensor Fusion Mapping Robot</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*Main Tasks：
Built a complete SLAM mapping system (data preprocessing, front-end odometry, back-end optimization, loop detection) and successfully deployed it on a robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Front-end odometry:
Implemented a 30ms update rate front-end odometry using the Kalman gain update method from &amp;ldquo;FAST-LIO2&amp;rdquo; and the use of ikdtree (balanced binary tree) reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Back-end optimization:
Used the GTSAM factor graph optimization library based on ISAM2 to fuse Lidar, IMU, and RTK data, achieving global optimization of indoor and outdoor poses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Loop detection:
Used both Euclidean distance-based loop detection and ScanContext-based global descriptor loop detection methods. Loop detection was performed in an independent thread, and the overall mapping process was parallel in structure, with a low frequency loop retrieval rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Accuracy evaluation:
Tested on public datasets both indoors and outdoors. For indoor testing data, the algorithm was able to significantly eliminate map shadow and height error compared to FASTLIO2. For outdoor testing data, the calculated trajectory and RTK positioning results were unified in the ENU coordinate system and evaluated with EVO trajectory error assessment, with an RMSE of 0.3m.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
